One modern answer to the question, is simply math
is the set of theorems of ZFC set theory.
Where ZFC stands for Zermelo, Fraenkel plus Choice, and is axiomatized
by these set of axioms. We will answer why these particular
axioms later, but for now just know that these are the
best attempt to formalize all of mathematics into a single language.
The theory of ZFC is every logical consequence of
these axioms, which we can think of as all
outputs of a certain special theorem proving computer.
So, we feed in the axioms, and it outputs the
logical consequences of these axioms, which we call the theorems.
Then we can feed these theorems back in as
input, and we continue deriving new mathematical theorems.
So, there is some pre-existing space of all possible proofs
from this set of axioms, and the goal of mathematics
is to explore as much of this space as possible.
There are multiple ways of formalizing what
the inside of this theorem proving computer.
Perhaps the simplest is with the so called Hilbert Calculus, which
is just this set of axioms equipped with modus ponens.
These axioms determine the behaviour of the logical negation, implication,
and universal quantifier, and they turn out to be all
that we need to formalize first order logic.
Modus ponens, can be seen as the application of a computer program,
where phi implies psi means that it takes in phi and outputs
psi, so if we then feed in phi we get psi.
Not rocket science. But the necessary complexity comes from the fact
that we can pass functions as input to other functions.
So we can design or derive, complex interconnect
circuits of logical variables using these axioms.
And this set of axioms is of a special kind, since
it can only prove logically valid statements, and as Godel proved
in 1929, it can prove all logically valid first order statements.
So, we can think of these set of axioms, known as the
logical axioms, as the operating system of our theorem proving computer.
Then we add in new symbols specific to our given theory
to the language, add axioms controlling these symbols and we feed
in new axioms to our theorem prover and let it run.
This view of mathematics aligns with the formalist view
of math, namely that it is a game being
played by meaningless symbols according to certain rules.